all right welcome to our and we all said
that's on the agenda to rename these and
figure out what we named them so we can
do a thumbnail for them but I'll just
say fix our world Friday met a project
meeting at the moment we're live for the
first time on both Facebook and YouTube
so we'll see how that does for
technology I don't know if it uses more
bandwidth when that happens and there is
he can add himself actually if he wants
to or I can add him there we go so he's
like crazy hair just came from at a
meeting and haven't had ties right
you're looking very I'd ask yeah all
right good to hear I expect there to be
more brilliance with that hair that
there's a direct correlation it's also
absolutely it's like the brain power
pushes the hair out and it sticks out
that's my excuse for my whole life all
right so we're live for the first time
on both Facebook and YouTube it's funny
because it's post it as you on Facebook
make sure there's I guess it's your
profile picture right on the Facebook
one so one of the things we need we
don't need to but could discuss today is
naming this meeting whatever it is and
then I can do a thumbnail so that can be
what is because both on YouTube where
it's just gray and on on Facebook where
it shows your picture I think it's
better to have one that being said I
made one for our solution raising there
was the two brains and I think less
people click on it because it's not a
picture of us like they don't actually
know what it is and so it's like one
versus the other but it could just be
maybe a picture of us a thumbnail and I
could use that as and then we could name
that whatever the thing is something
like the last time I don't know it was
possibly just the way that I did the
thumbnail where it kind of looks like
it's gonna be an explanation cartoon as
opposed a conversation whereas if we
name this something much more clear than
solution raising then yeah then doing
the thumbnail it could be the best
all sports not it looks more perhaps
slightly more professional because I'm
not great at making the thumbnails but I
can do it I've been doing it and then
hopefully next week last night as I'm
sure both of you realized I posted our
project consume wasn't posting it
oh sorry group thanked group projects
and so we now have twenty members and
that is from no MIT nobody commenting on
it's about eight people liking it and
Jim not being the one to post it so I
think it will be a popular group if it
when Jim posts it or we're able to help
the algorithm salience and what we want
yes sorry badly you were gonna say
something let's just say he also hasn't
added to the game B homepage yet but I
imagine that'll happen yes exactly and
then people can see what the different
project or the different groups are and
I think projects is one that most people
want to join because they're either
looking for a project that in the Soglin
t1 are the two and then the wiki just
because that's if they want to help get
it if the like team together and the
information they've also asked me to be
in an min on the game B page or men and
moderator utter action of the difference
between I think moderator and and I was
like oh let's try I can't really type a
lot during the day so I'm like as long
as it's not a lifelong commitment I can
pull out without getting be falling
apart yes I will try I don't know what
that had to do anything but so I think
last week we had talked about having
instead of this kind of being a board
meeting and having more of a topic and
then talking about that so that anyone
could come and join and so the topic we
had picked for this week or briefly
discussed last week was poking holes in
omega rule was figuring out i'd like
codes of conduct that we want to holder
in these but that might be something we
want to start doing but more solidifying
what this meeting looks like for when
people come in join what are
the rules or when they're on camera
versus just in the comments right like
everyone can watch right now in the
comments or not zero viewers but the
yeah if they become a couple times or
can they just watch a couple get the
gist of it and then say yes I am
comfortable I know what is going on and
then Wednesday I think we're fine and
with that rule where you have to have
attended in order to go I don't think we
start there because I'm Blu's trying to
get people to show up we do kind of want
that to be a low bar and then over time
especially if we're starting to see
people show up that have no idea how
anything works we're like all right
let's start to talk about some
requirements for what you have to have
done and the the level of participation
the level of participation you have to
have shown in order to show up so I
guess part of it is what is our
objective for this not this hour but
this our ongoing right it's what from
what I understand it's to move the
matter project forward and yet not move
them in a project forward right we're
not having this be a board meeting for
like where's our next steps it's more
how can we bring people to a meeting
where you're representing your project
you're also you and then how do we
discuss a topic that will generate more
interest generate like you want to
participate in and then from there once
we have more participation we kind of
figure out the first like I've already
do this is already the Menna project
right media and having a conversation
it's the Facebook group and but the
first thing we make together right that
might be tech related op related a
spreadsheet related right like could be
literally anything already doing those
things so yes thoughts comments or do we
want to start a topic and talk about
content so I think one thing is I
believe there was talk about alternating
did this meeting so we do still have a
board meeting but I think we said it
probably doesn't need to be every week
and then every other week we alternate
something else that's not board meeting
but is you know together tech met a
project related
yeah it looked like you were going to
say come no I yeah I forgotten now but I
think you're right we were gonna do
alternating topic I just couldn't
remember which time was for which
meetings cuz we talked about some of the
different options yeah I need to write
something down next time so so the idea
is both of our weekly meetings are
alternating so the Saturday one is
project raising one week solution
raising the next and we might also be
doing tiny differences right I think in
a one month period having two of those
at two o'clock and two of those at nine
o'clock is good for our Australia and
New Zealand the European people can kind
of come to either depending on which one
is right of course for them but doing it
that way and then this one's at 11:00
a.m. and we're alternating between
having it be a topic that people can
come to and have a conversation you
don't need to know what's going on with
the Mehta project and a board meeting
type how do we move them at a project
forward it sounds like this meetings a
little bit of both as we hammer that out
right and I think like as you've said
they're both both versions at the
meeting that were alternated that we're
alternating between there's all them are
still involved with the Mehta project
one of them is the board meeting how do
we want to operate and what are the
rules and then the other one will be the
topics to do like what problems are we
trying to solve what questions are we
trying to answer to do with the Mehta
project and you know the kinds of things
that would that we'd be talking about
and like the obvious example that jumps
to my mind is trust whereas they at some
point we want to have a conversation
around what does it mean to be able to
trust an app well what does it mean to
be able to trust like the DPP the
information etc topics that are more
they touch many of the projects exactly
one of the problems that we're trying to
solve for projects in general which
would be you know take either tack
reasons go or book with a wiki election
all them after I sort of have that
concept of
what do we need to do for you to trust
us trust us dammit
that works we're done world song let's
call it a day go to Hawaii celebrate and
call it a day
alright so do we want to actually set a
schedule as in for both this and the
tomorrow one toros of course the project
raising for Ritchie's project culture
creation and then the week after we are
doing I've yet to post it in game B but
the solution raising do we want that
solution raising to be a to or do we
want it you already mean like do we want
to two's and then to nines or you want
to nine to nine I think you kind of have
to like - nine - nine wouldn't work
unless we're planning on having like
projects always be at nine and solutions
always being at two he might go nine
nine two - yeah I'm fine with either way
like it's okay
might want to try it - like well one or
two times before we like to think about
do we want this to be a regular thing
because if no one shows up there's no
you know there's no there's no movement
than men but it feels like it's way
better than maybe we just mmm all - yeah
well part of the reason I'm not having
them it - is I don't want my day my two
days I have off with my kid to be right
in the middle but I can't do anything
really before and I can't really do
anything after um with my health
challenges as well anyone else can
figure out how to work around two
o'clock but um so doing it twice a month
is fine but I don't want to do it every
Saturday at 2:00 but that also could
mean that like if that is what we decide
and that's what moves the project
forward I just come to every other one
and if full disclosure probably be the
solution raises because those are the
ones that that I enjoy I just not sure I
enjoy all of them it's it's really fun
to see someone's project but also the
solution raises have a little bit more
of my heart I love it
although I'm really looking forward to
Richie's one tomorrow so do we are we
going to do it
just on a case-by-case basis like
whoever we kind of have lined up if
they're australian we'll do it at 2:00
and otherwise it's an eye and then
nothing how the 2 p.m. goes and we
adjust from there the end goal is just
to move the project forward if we try
that too and you know there's better
traction there's an argument to be made
for having it a to more often all right
I might not be able to make tomorrow
I'll try but something commit during
that time you know I believe since it's
a to the other person we have this in
that part of the hemisphere is Kylie and
she has a project comments trust I'm
gonna butcher the name but she also
wants to do a project raising on that
and I want to do one on that too it's a
really cool concept and to hers would be
at 2 p.m. as well and she's coming to
Ritchie's I believe tomorrow and then
she might come to a solution racing as
well cool and you you said she's it in
or near the same time zone
she's yes she's in Australia so she's
not ridiculously waking up at 3 a.m.
no there are
yonas doesn't Ritchie also like yonis is
in New Zealand and they're in like
Melbourne so there's a couple hours
difference between but both ridiculously
early yeah dealing with this time zone
thing alright do we want to talk about
codes of conduct that's mine you want to
come put the name first yeah yeah name
would be great
that's it is the name for what start for
this for dwelling breakfast do both of
them though I guess so we want a name
for when we have the meta project like
the board meeting and one room we have a
topic that is more relevant well we
might
want to do I mean maybe not I'll run it
by you since idea cafe is more my baby
but Colleen the one that is topic
related idea cafe and even running it in
the same type of format where we for
made a question or not and just have a
topic but everyone takes a brief part to
share in the beginning and then just
have an open discussion for the rest of
it or is that is that resonate with you
cuz then I feel like it's not
introducing yet another concept yeah I
think that's worth trying out and again
you know we can see if the fact that
that word is already falling around if
that helps you know piggyback on that
understanding and then this meeting is
still the D board meeting so we
alternate between the board meetings and
the idea kept X perfect and I already
have a little I already have the logo
Dennis made smoke and and then yeah it's
just because it's just about crafting
the topic into a question which helps
focus it anyway and hold on stabilize it
like trust how do we build trust with
our customers right and then we need
it's not about having the right answer
it's about having a space to share ideas
off a look at meets another tag like is
theirs idea cafe the channel and then
it's we talk about game B every Tuesday
on there but they're not we're not
talking about projects rockin what can
be as a whole
Facebook group from Davey in the future
and anyone can come to that one this one
is theoretically designed people to
bring their projects to and represent
their project so I mean idea cafe
projects or Enterprise occurred for can
be projects or yes that's something like
that was not just idea cafe I think that
make sense it's very wordy but it gets
the point across definitely you know
more concise names but that at least it
gets the point across
yes and then what do we want to
that's good for now so what do we want
to call our meta project or meeting I
think this is fine for now I think it
won't really gather tech board meeting
the yeah perfect and then when we lay it
out like that - it'll be a lot easier to
also people know which one to come to
the calendar on the Facebook site is
still very like I don't have to add it
to the events have a new event every
time because you can't have the same
event with a different URL that people
are going it like it's a little weird
but having one calendar that does say
what we're doing as it comes up and
people can like watch here participate
here because especially if it's the UM
like I there's clearly gonna be a lower
I think a lower barrier for
participation to the idea cafe then to
the board meeting right like I probably
need to know what's going on with them
to be at the board meeting you don't
necessarily need to know what's going on
with you can come and just have a
project to participate in that idea cafe
you just maybe need to know then the
basic structure which is in that heart
I've been it's up to five minutes each
share then open conversation so together
tech board meeting thumbnail which I
might do with with a picture of the four
of us me you like with the onus and just
take it out of one of our ones on yeah I
won't think I'd be able to take it out
of one of these ones cuz I don't have
access to the YouTube channel
behind the scenes um and I don't want to
because I think it would get me out of
my idea cafe and proud of democracy
which I don't know what um so anyway I
can take a picture a screenshot from one
of those videos and just make a can be a
placeholder for now so people can kind
of see what it looks like cuz otherwise
I'm working with their their thumbnails
and a lot of them are like people and
and like things that don't really work
for what we're doing so I think having
art for faces actually works
or medians if we're close across it or
whatever I'll figure it up it won't be
perfect but it will be a please older
and so do we want them to set what we
next week this was kind of a board
meeting mm-hmm is next week we want to
have an idea cafe yeah sure and do we
want to pick a topic slash question that
might be the easiest or we can pick
three and then send it to vote I'm fine
either way
so it's about three that we think are
promising I think there is also because
we're already asking the three questions
for the solution raising I wonder if we
just want to pick it for the first one
or two and then wait until we start
getting an audience in the actual
channel and then start posting questions
there once we actually have like people
interacting and more members and that
kind of thing so how do we want to I
think Trust is trust resonate with
everyone as something that's definitely
be top of my list so I'm not sure if
it's the same for everyone else but so
then we just need to craft it into a
type of question that anyone can answer
which is just right I think how can we
get strangers to trust us in our
projects I was thinking like what do you
need to trust an organization or
something like that where it's like you
protect because I can't necessarily
answer what people need to trust you
know quickly election or reason score
but I can say what I need in order to
trust you know Google or wiki election
or anything else yeah no I think that's
an important because it's easier to
answer is the individual like you I have
this I also have an opinion of what I
would trust in entres I clearly admit a
trust wiki lection and reasons for more
than a random other one because I know
the two of you right and so that's very
different than it's like but yeah I can
how that is my that's right I need to
know the person and have a conversation
with them to trust better
their app right yeah I feel for the kind
of person they are but it comes into
play
yeah so what do you need to trust what
do you need to trust an organization is
that it clear enough when we haven't
have this conversation maybe what do you
need what do you need what if it's like
what what builds your trust an
organization what what do you need in
place to trust an organization and do
wanna say it's like four new
organizations or do it I'm thinking of
it is for it to be as broad as possible
so like you know we'll probably start
out with maybe some examples of like
well here's what caused me to lose trust
in organization so the opposite of that
and then what okay on top of that maybe
things we haven't seen like for me I
have a lot of questions up because it's
not just what do you need in order to
trust in organization what I think a lot
of us are getting at is what do you need
both to trust the outcome and to be
willing to contribute both your time and
or like actually you know some money on
patreon or Kickstarter or whatever what
do you need to see what questions do you
have what makes you go from there to
like okay I'll support that and so maybe
because this is also our first one do we
want to focus that do we want to pick
because that's gonna be all very
different right who do I trust to fund
their project who do I trust to use
their product once it's in existence who
do I trust to be part of creating their
project my time and once it's already
out there and I have no involvement in
it but I want to be just a customer
right what I do I yeah I mean I think
it's good to start broad and just say
what do you need to trust the
organization and then people can say
what that means to them somebody else
might say like here's what you know
Google could do to make me trust them
and then somebody else can say well a
brand new organization here's what I
would need this trust that organization
I think that is generally how I word it
is it's not a you it's an AI so what do
I cause you're answering the question
right it's like what do I need to trust
an organization yeah we've just this
slightly different word any but alright
so next week Leben am i d academe and
post it in the projects and or just the
projects actually I think because then
those are the people we want to we're
not coming into the edgy ihcafe oh and I
think it'll be a good way but I can also
host under it an example of like regular
idea cafe some people who haven't seen
one can kind of get a feel for and
because they're all game be ones anyway
for the last like two months we've got a
lot to choose from that are game BS yeah
all right and then Oros project raising
the week after solution raising which
I'm putting up the question for we have
more than half an hour left so if we
wanted we can like I said this could be
a hybrid we can discuss the other thing
on the agenda which was Oh topics or
visit topics if we want to discuss in
future idea cafes right yeah so we could
just continue doing that and and
brainstorm topics and just keep this
being more of a board meeting or we can
talk about code of conduct and poking
holes in a rule so I feel like with that
topic I want other people because I want
other people to poke holes we make a
rule like the three of us I think are
comfortable poking holes in projects and
you know I mean like in each other's but
it's like when you bring your baby to us
and asking all of us what like I want to
poke holes in people's projects and I
want people to poke holes in my projects
but I don't want to poke holes in
people's projects that don't want all
spoke to them right so it's how much
truth do you want on your project and
what is comfortable what's not
comfortable and how do we actually put
that into place using omega rule and yet
not using omega roll right so yeah okay
this start or the answer that is what's
the purpose of these session if you
don't want to poke holes don't bring
your project a project raising if you
just want people to say good things
about your project you have a mirror at
home like go handle that you're actually
trying to build it and move forward and
they said like that in my mind like I
wouldn't attend something that someone
is like I don't want any negative
feedback or constructive criticism just
tell me good things
like that's cool that's fine that you
want that I'll pass I feel like I'd be
really cool if someone came and said
that I would then know the rule and be
like okay I can do that the issue is
when people feel bad and in no way
communicate that and then you're poking
holes in it and it's going like what not
poking why I mean even when we first
introduced project raising it was
actually under it was like well practice
Omega rule will tell you about the
beauty of your project and then we you
say the aspirations right if you're part
of your aspirations or clearly things we
need to pull holes in then we almost
have like we can't meet that aspiration
without doing that but if the aspiration
is help me find the value in this then
we're not finding the opposite right
we're not finding the holes we're
finding the value but I want permission
to poke holes like I want to be them to
be like yes
anything goes I don't want to have to
guess as a participant right I want to
know what the level is that you want
right
yeah well poked in and holes I want you
to see anything yes
we almost provide like a menu of like
here's the kind of feedback we can offer
pick which ones as opposed to like only
good things I only want positive
feedback and for you to say that my idea
is great there's multiple ways that you
can frame feedback like instead of
saying that won't work saying have you
thought about this it's not really
poking a hole but it still kind of is
and so it's like how do you want that
frame I guess I'm just trying to avoid
the I only want good things just tell me
my ideas great and that I can keep going
well there's there's times in a project
where it's not of much value to point
out all the potential problems but to
try and add you know depth to the idea
or or something in that value and I also
sometimes find it's counterproductive
when people talk about Edra when you
said have you thought about this now
that a lot of that's good
but everyone small it's like Oh have you
thought about doing this it's like in
the same area of your project
but completely unrelated to what you're
doing and it's like yeah that's a good
idea but it's not what I'm interested in
right yeah I think all the feedback
should be going back to what they want
to get out of it and so like if you're
trying to get you know I'm trying to get
funding okay great so we'll keep that in
mind and you say okay well there's this
thing you might be able to do that isn't
really what you're doing but it's like
parallel or analogous or close enough
and might help funding so but you
wouldn't say that if that wasn't what
they want so maybe if we do keep kind of
the concept of asking what are your
aspirations or what do you want out of
this and have them mention that they
should probably say I want critical
feedback as one of those things on the
idea or if I just want a brainstorm how
to meet this goal you know so it's
closer to a solution raising than a
project right raising well they might
have a germ of an idea or if started and
that way we can kind of get a feeling
and maybe propose a couple of those
aspirations for people to choose from
right because I'm part of what is the
issue I find when I'm when I'm
interacting with somebody on my idea I
don't have a problem with them poking
holes in it at all I want to have an
hour-long conversation where they're
poking holes in it the issue is if every
conversation is always that then they're
poking the same holes in it again and
again and again and it's like I've dealt
with it yes I've thought of that yes
I've done and so part of it is like it's
not don't poke holes it's like yes I get
that I guess that's a problem we'll
figure that out later or I have figured
it out but I'm not getting into that oh
and part of this is for the project
raising right when someone brings their
project they can give us their
aspirations but part of this is also for
the Facebook group what are what is the
code of conduct life of like posting in
there about your project
I think yay but with that there how much
will be poking holes in it and what kind
of holes right like the community rules
for if I post a ball
Wiki election in game b projects the
kinds of comments that were wanting like
what is allowed what isn't allowed
what's the point what's like not even
necessary the rules remember was
involved but like what do we actively
want what kind of feedback do we want
that yeah because I mean the Facebook
group itself isn't really the place to
get every like every poked a hole and
then fix the hole and poke like it's
just not designed for that type of
conversation right it's even like the
Facebook Messenger is hard to do you
have that that manually and then the
ones with more holes you're gonna get
the algorithm it's gonna be higher
anyway and it's like how often is wiki
election yet like I think that if you
have a problem and you want help right
and say hey theoretically hopefully we
know what wiki election is right already
and then it's like this is the thing I'm
dealing with and posting that sound
screen then we can help you cuz you gots
an actual question or you post what is
wiki lection and then you put the call
out for what you want right like if I'm
posting my ideas I actually don't I want
people to comment some of the algorithm
to be increased but I don't want to have
the conversation there because I don't
find it useful I want to have an actual
conversation I think the conversation in
the group should be trying to arrange
these kinds of meetings where it's like
we all projects what goal were trying to
solve over three are trying to solve the
same thing right let's set up some kind
of a live stream or arrange some kind of
a more in-depth conversation that's not
through facebook comments because that's
not very useful
yeah but this is all kind of making me
think back through the hundreds of
conversations just like you to where
you're trying to explain the project and
it's a very frustrating experience some
of that is because it takes a while for
us to learn how to express it away but
also a lot of people do too like I can
imagine Adria when when you do your idea
and someone comes and says oh that's
never going to stop all misinformation
and you're like well okay yeah I don't
do miracles but it will make the world
better right yeah I don't like to say
let's let's just have a blanket
understanding that no one's project is
going to be perfect and has to solve the
problem a hundred percent yeah I think
it's very reasonable to make a list of
feedback that's not useful like that's
not a perfect solution that is not
useful feedback yeah so I think it'd be
good to make a little guidebook of that
and also not like Jubilee was saying you
don't have to have a solution to every
potential I mean a lot of people seem to
be just like here's the wall you're
gonna have to climb over here's a wall
you're gonna have to climb over and it's
like yeah I mean I've seen that wall but
I'm not a every mention of the wall they
phrase it like that's a reason not to do
it right like this is going to stop you
as opposed have you thought about this
yeah yeah yeah so yeah I'm working it'd
be interesting to work up a document a
short document on hear some feedback
that's not generally useful and how to
write re you know get that same idea
across like a tree like you said do we
consider this yet right I think that
will end up being from a living document
where as we're going through this for
various projects a we're gonna end up
identifying kind of stages where we're
like okay so your project is in this
stage based on the kinds of content and
the you know your capability to explain
it like if you're having problems
explaining your project okay then you're
not at this stage yet you're here or
earlier
because in order for you to be you know
at stage three or four you need to be
able to like it you know explain at high
level in ten seconds okay cool so then
we'll go back a stage and start talking
about your framework and sort of help
it has show and as you get further along
you're more like a you'll probably have
a catalog of here's the things people
have asked and here's the common answers
to it let's not handle the questions
that this person has has already
answered and so there will probably be a
bit of like pre pretty research before
we actually do those where we're saying
all right here's you know a ten minute
review of their article on their project
to say here's the common questions
here's the answers let's not cover those
questions because I've got those handled
and I think the more structure the
person posting for feedback gives the
better like like how we help them set
out aspirations right like what I'm
looking for is overall feedback what I'm
looking for is you to tell me on the
savior of humanity alright just like I
don't do anything wrong you got to write
that up good good just accolades where's
my cult members yeah yeah cuz I majored
sorry there we go yeah sometimes you
just have an idea and it's like you've
kicked it around and yeah and sometimes
you don't want could it's more like what
can we do to make this happen
and so yeah yeah so maybe the you know
defining some stages and yeah guidance
obviously it may end up being just like
we'll have a catalog of like who knows
what so if we're saying oh you want a
session on funding great we have you
know these four three people who have
done funding and who are experts and
blah blah blah you may also have a like
here's the experts here's their skill
levels and here's the kinds of feedback
that they tend to give like that
person's a whole poker
you don't want whole spoke don't talk to
them because that's what they're gonna
do that's their skill set yeah I'm not I
don't know how to not do you want all
the things that are wrong with it cuz
that's what I want to do it's yeah
is this skill set if you
that horrible if you don't and there
might be a good questionnaire also
before we do and maybe this is good for
the project raising at some point is
like what are some common feedback that
you get that you have answers to and do
you want to take a little bit of your
time upfront to cover that or do you
want to just know that you have a
thought it'll be solved in the future
but it's not the focus of this yeah
right and then also what happens if we
have they're like here's the questions
and here's the answers and we read it
and we're like that doesn't answer that
question is that's very flexible realize
yeah really get the explanation like
where it's almost challenging that's
their stage for like much better term
like you think you have this sorted we
all read it and none of us understand it
yeah so maybe whether they want to
explore that right now because they may
know their answers not great right yeah
I think the other part to keep in mind
is that this isn't just about the
project that's coming on this is also
about our you know the the the together
tech journey of figuring out what does
it take to assess a project to be able
to sort of structure them to be able to
set up what are the stages like be able
to test it up what kind of feedback
actually leads to useful learnings if we
go through five of them or like you know
what poking holes works like it's it's
given us our best stuff why are we doing
this if we're not trying to move things
forward and you might end up with here's
the kinds of feedback if you really
don't want this okay here's the other
options but they aren't as good in our
explanation you want those either okay
this isn't the session for you because
here's what we're trying to get out of
this session as well it's not just about
what the project wants out of it we're
trying to work we can quite possibly not
necessarily the three of us but the
bigger group as a whole have different
types of sessions that are like this is
a project raising when you're looking
for funding this is a project raising
for marketing and this is like a
beginning and you just had the problem
and you it's your baby solution because
it's like very helpful actually to poke
holes in the baby solution because
nothing's been done yet and so like it's
both helpful and not helpful depending
on the person whereas hey this is my app
that I'm releasing it to more
and your leg did you think about I don't
care if it breaks it let's just release
it because the the works been done the
money's there right like cubes spa needs
$250,000 to move forward saying don't
start isn't an option right like it's
like you've already put in all of this
time and yet I know I'm getting consent
and stuff all the time it's like no stop
you've put in all of your family's money
and this is not a profit project and
it's up to that person to kind of like
listen listen or not and and decide is
this worth the risk
right it's different because we're we
are attempting game B so it's like in
the case of cubes bond it might not be
financially lucrative for James to
continue for the planet and society I
really want him to continue right right
and so it's like how and that's part of
like the Better Project how do we fund
things how do we get people's projects
made that have huge impact that don't
necessarily that need more funding or
don't have the story figured out don't
have the media piece right that there
it's not the charismatic leader that
wants to wants to be on YouTube and
wants to get followers yeah although
it's just thinking it would be
interesting to have a YouTube channel
that features these projects so they
don't have to do it
which is kind of what we're doing yeah
they can take it a step further and you
know have like okay so here's our
monthly update from this person and
talking about or their project is that
might be interesting to watch and then
you end up with is like this might be
once we have you know a couple projects
on board some were only together tech
website there's like project profiles
where it's like you know here's what
wiki election here's who's involved
here's where it's at here's the content
but a lot
here's reason score here's who's
involved here's where it's at here's the
content and so as we bring projects on
we're like oh you know for example
here's like the funding conversation for
reason score what are they talking about
funding where's this at oh you can go
watch the other eight sessions that we
talked about regions go over here if you
be able to see each of the stages that
went through and the timeline or if you
just want to see where we're right now
just watch the live session or watch the
most recent one so we're talking about
marketing there might be group market I
think you'd almost end up with like a a
database that you can look at multiple
ways you're like oh I want to see all be
marketing sessions because that's what
I'm interested in
great here's the four projects that were
you talk to about marketing for or you
say I want to just see what reason
scores up do okay here's the five things
that we've had on reason score one of
them is marketing yeah I'm just thinking
there's I mean it's still all kind of
process based I think there's there
could be value in just creating short
five-minute videos on each project every
month on the status update and do it in
kind of like a you know like a news
reporter yeah and the beat is this is
this game be project space I mean
especially if it was like five minutes
maximum and try to keep it under - but
like five minutes maximum tell us what
you got up to in the last month right
where is it what do you need like we can
happen I I would like to have a format
for it right and if you don't follow the
format okay but like name of my project
is gonna be in the title it's like where
what it were what did I say I was gonna
do last month I don't know what this
format actually is but having a format
would be helpful yeah well the
interesting thing is that conversation
that started in I think it may have just
been game B or now they're talking about
like how do we build our own
crowdsourcing platform this seems like
you'd like that we're basically starting
to plan the project page where like if
you're going to go in to go look at the
profile for a reason score what kind of
content is on there one of the big
things is here's the most recent update
from Bentley on reason score so if you
want to see where it's at great go watch
that two-minute video well hey we're
doing a task we're doing this we've
talked about this our next step is this
although I yeah the concept I was
thinking of was just a little different
it's not necessarily from that person
it's
or from here's a journalist they're
creating content and they're beat is
this so they would they it and be
helpful to those founders who are
looking to make people aware what's
going on right if they don't they may
not have the skill set to run the
YouTube channel at the time yes I think
that person comes about that would be
awesome
like if that's someone's skill set where
they're like I loves talking about other
people's projects and I can make it
succinct and they're part of this so
that it's you don't I mean they
understand what's going on with reasons
whether they understand cuz like they
have to get the information and and then
do that for now it makes more sense to
have the person with the project do it
and honor we're all gonna be completely
different in our skill level in just
doing that right like here's where it's
at and here's what I need and that's
part of kind of at least my vision of
together tech is like right now under
game a you have to be everything for
your project be the spokesperson you
have to be perfect you have to edits
like that is broken in and of itself you
know I mean like James Jones is amazing
at the engineering stuff I want that
project to exist he might not be the
best at being the person to go into
medians and get funding or to go into
meetings you know like and yet he should
absolutely be the person doing what he's
doing and I'm the same way for my stuff
like I can think this in my sleep I
could come up with tech ideas that can
change the world I can't make them and I
can't even communicate them and that's
broken look it's like that doesn't work
you can't have an idea and not be able
to communicate it and hope it gets into
the world but I'm figuring that P so
like showcasing that journey as well of
like right even if you can't communicate
and communicate it for now until someone
comes on board and wants to communicate
yours and we can do that and we find the
holes right someone needs marketing for
this someone needs this and it's finding
the people who're the projects in the
projects with the people it right I
think one of my goals for together Tech
and the Amanar project is to sort of
have that library of like here's things
that did you know each project is trying
or some of the projects are trying right
so some of them might be Oh some of them
are trying doing project raises some of
them are trying this monthly updated
video some of them are trying this and
then you can see who's trying it you can
see the content and you can sort of see
their feedback on you know
they think it helps if it's easy to do
how much time is taking them how many
views it gets like whatever kinds of
things we want to track to see if it's
working but in my mind that's one of the
things that together Tech can give to
projects is that library of like here
are some ideas that you know the various
project owners have started doing and
that they wanted to do and then here's
other projects like if Bentley starts
doing the monthly update video and I see
that I'm like I like that and then I
start doing it as somebody else sees it
and they start doing it so five out of
the ten projects have it great let's
track that let's you know have some spot
to show it and blah blah blah and you
can show it on the project itself and
you can show it wherever else but start
to build that library of like here's
ideas of what we're doing you know both
get both communicate where the project
is at and possibly build a following
yeah no I like it it's yeah possibly I
mean we can't even be on the Facebook
page I mean just posting it is one thing
and it's gonna get lost it's gonna be
but having like a document where it is
like this is figuring out how to do that
in the spreadsheet or how to do that
where it's like here is I don't know if
you can link a spreadsheet on Facebook I
think you can like here's all medleys
ones friend here's the dates right in
here's and if it's not filled out like
if Bentley doesn't do those ones it's
not going to be filled out if he does
them every three months you're gonna see
that it's every three months could also
do is like if we're saying okay every
month we want the update great on the
first or last err seventeenth they had a
month when you put like you know a
pinned post in that channel saying okay
everybody post your updates here and
then a that thread gets popular and B
you can sort of see everyone who's
posting at a certain point it gets
unwieldy and in my case that's what I
want I want to sort having those
problems of like thirty-eight people
just posted their updates let's move
this somewhere yeah yeah no that's it
sounds like a good a good option and
having it be the normal that it's a
video one right that it's like and yet
if you're not comfortable with that
do voice no next right like it's like do
what you can but it's not a hierarchy of
videos the best because we can see you
get to know you the trust is established
and it doesn't necessarily need to be
outside of this group right like you can
post an unlisted YouTube video and we
can watch it and nobody else will and
that's fine if that's what you want to
do or post it publicly so your all your
people can see it right it's like partly
having that that um not level and and
having it be yeah like I mean even if we
just start doing that right and I'm like
I don't even have a project my projects
all the meta projects okay it's like
everything my projects need I just
changed my youtube channel with the
farmers
did you believe saves the world by
meandering through life to treat the
meta project like a project so if you
want to be the one to do that that's fun
of me yeah I don't know how is the other
part of my updating what have I done
well it's it been a mod it's like it's
been a week since the Kyle sees thing
and dealing with the neighbor drama and
I'm like like life is both very slow for
me and superfast at the same time like
it's like okay I'm having fun I'm
enjoying life our fire alarm was going
off for two nights TRO it's like I don't
know how to give it on I just did it I
don't know how thank you the update on
the project without also updating you on
my life which is why my channel networks
without together tech there as I'm just
gonna save the world where I meander
through life don't mind me um but yeah I
can figure out I can figure it out I can
figure out a project like hey we did a
Facebook group right I think at least
for the first while it's better if
everyone is kind of doing their own spin
because then we start to get an idea of
okay people love Bentley's updates what
is he doing what's unique about his
updates that people just love them and
then the runs the Adriel does no one
cares even though people like the
project like you start to learn what
works and what doesn't and then every
time you post do you like okay let's do
a monthly updates that post will also
link out to like the proposed
instructions like here's the D things
that we want
here's alternate ideas that people are
trying just some general like if this is
the first when you're doing go read this
okay great here's the frame
there should be as sort of as short as
possible and concise and like here's
what like we were heavily ask people to
do even you know being on videos not
required but heavily recommended and the
other things are like just random things
you can try if you want yeah like if I
can do I'll do it
so if we want to take on over the next
week once about leans back on camera and
can degree and we let us know as well to
just do a first video right and if we
post if we post that post in facebook in
the puck the game be projects and for
the call out and then we post under it
our update for our projects which I can
do the matter project one and then the
idea Cafe itself is kind of also one but
their matter projects a project it needs
to have someone represent it so I'm
willing to be that person idea Cafe is
my project only because I don't have
another one right like it's like okay
well it's something to move forward and
I'm here just have a conversation I'm
here to just like live my life and
figure it out and it's a weird update
and I have a YouTube channel and I'm
okay like but it's it's um I mean I can
do one for it be a cafe like here's what
I plan on doing in the next month and
here's where it's at right now if you're
doing it for idea cafe we can also
alternate through us because yeah the
like together tech might also be a good
example of a more complex project as a
it's a project about projects and B
there's already more of us like that's
something unique about it I think a lot
of the other projects don't have almost
all the other projects that I've seen or
like it's one person it's their baby
take hey I got that already has a board
which I don't think many others do and
so it's we actually have the ability to
say like it's off all three of us or
four of us and who you know whoever else
joins then we can start to say like oh
here's what we're trying for multi
people projects and that's you know
probably a later stage or like one of
the things to track on a project is
there's more than one project owner
here's how we're handling that yeah
that's that's true so um can we do a
guideline I mean we have like 10 minutes
left a guideline of what we want and
those updated it knows monthly we just
do our own first because if we're if
we're all
just doing our own I think the only
guideline is under five minutes under
five minutes and like you know
preferably under - but like definitely
under five I guess like what are we
covering in that is it literally
anything or is it like hey I explained
Enix we've never explained like because
I actually did and it wasn't nobody
caught I can even delete it we could do
a new one but like what is your project
and I have listed a few things it was
like what's your name what's your
project where's the link outside and
nobody answered I might have been too
much stuff but like hey if we're like
upload an explainer video not a
professional one you'll see you don't
like it's like this level of hey what is
together tech what is idea cafe right um
which is because that's not it's the
where were ass but you kind of need that
to get to the where we're at right and
then it's like and then the next one is
like where are you right where are you
right now what stage is there maybe we
want like the you know you should
include your elevator pitch at the start
of your your your explainer and like
that so you know and we might end up not
having that be everyone because maybe
that's too much but we'll all spread out
with okay you start out with your
elevator pitch and then you go into like
where your project is at you the first
one will probably just be aware that
right now and then future ones are let's
move since the last update and you'll
select a combination of where things are
at now like if there's any you know
thing that might bridge multiple videos
and sort of current projects are like
curtain yeah a project within the front
a task I guess is a better would say
know what task you're working on right
now etc yeah so for the first remember
because we're putting the call-out group
to do these that like give us your
elevator pitch give us your brief brief
explanation for what your project is who
you are and like know hey I'm Jubilee
I'm representing this month the meta
project which is you know we've been
meeting for a few months we are figuring
out what tools are going to be in common
that we all need what solutions can we
solve together how can we create all new
in salute
one we just started the Facebook group
we're doing trial and error as we go and
having hopefully have any fun along the
way right and that is where we're at so
I hope they've kind of the explainer and
where we're at and then what we're
looking to do is have more people join
and get involved in the meta project to
the much as they want to so it can also
help their personal project their
individual project um but that then it's
like the explainer the elevator pitch
and where you're at right at the
beginning stages and they were pretty
far along maybe what we do is the three
of us before or I guess what we're doing
the other session next week so beep beep
before the next board meeting in two
weeks we all do our own and then we
watch each other's and you know and
figure out so I'm like okay I like what
Bentley did there oh I didn't like what
Bentley did there oh I like H over there
I didn't like what their figure out what
we think you know what we like across
all them talk about that and the next
board meeting and then use those videos
of us actually doing it to come up with
the list of you know okay the five
minutes work or not even the five
minutes was too long or the elevator
pitch worked but you know this one was
too long and that one was maybe too
short like start to use real examples to
build the framework for okay so we just
did our first round of these here's what
we learned we're asking anybody else
that also wants to do this go make you
know your own video either just make it
on your own if you want us to learn with
net or if you want to follow our first
framework here's what we learned from
round one I definitely know two weeks
for us to do this in the Facebook group
I want to like have people submitting
videos right away because whatever even
if they're horrible if they're unlisted
we're watching them internally right so
it doesn't necessarily like I kind of
want to be like this is how
unprofessional it is you don't need to
get a video tog refer and edit it and
it's like stumble on your words your
elevator pitch is crap cool where are we
going from here right like it's like and
not as part of it it's like the
explainer video this is the best I got
this is the 30 second elevator pitch
it's gonna change from time to like
every time I say it and here's where
we're at and if I did another one it
would be probably completely different
cuz it's not scripted
you could script it if you wanted to
right but then we're having the met more
of the meta conversation on what works
what's it right like hey I watched yours
Bentley here's what I liked and here's
all the holes I'm poking in it so are we
saying do it do a 30-second pitch for
every update video or just the first and
also for the first especially so this is
like tell us what your project is and
where you're adding your project and fYI
we're gonna be looking to do these
monthly right so part of that is do the
first one and then when you and we know
where you're at where next month where
are you at what happened nothing I
didn't touch it I was super busy right
that's your update well most of the so
most of videos they'll assume that the
person is at least watch the first one
so they have the context and then it's
just enough day yeah I think the very
first video is like an extended elevator
pitch and then I would plan on every
video like you know 10 15 second
elevator pitch like super short right
like in mine it's trying to fight
misinformation and politics science and
news that's it yeah well I would go in2
bla bla bla but the first one might be a
little bit more you know in the politics
and news and this this this like doing a
bit more because it's the first one and
then you can go into where things are at
we'll figure that overtime to like if
you know I've watched three or four
Bentley's might be like okay it actually
does make sense to have the elevator
pitch or maybe that's a separate thing
you know we can figure it out as we're
doing them especially if we're watching
each other's then we can start to be
like okay I get it yeah maybe we don't
do the other yeah I just like the idea
sometimes we're not catching up with a
project to to binge-watch and the less
of an intro and an outro the easier the
been watching binge watching is I've
actually wanted to it'd be neat oh you
there might be a way to do this actually
but like in Netflix you can skip the
intro and then what happened last
episode right so kind of that we're like
here's a stir
of everything and then if I think that
people gonna stumble cross and then
individual video I might choose to throw
a head or an opening and a closing or
something but yeah yeah right if I give
my elevator pitch the beginning of each
one and I watch it and I know that was
30 seconds and then I share it from this
to 30-second mark if you don't know you
can go back and if you do know you just
watch forward yeah yeah I what we can
also do is if we do you know three to
five videos with an elevator pitch
we might each just go through our videos
pick our favorite one and make that a
standalone video and then that can be
using context for everything you want to
know what we collection is great go
watch this pretty second elevator pitch
you've seen it 30 times you don't watch
anymore
yeah and then each video going forward
is just like hey you know age we're
talking about wiki like Shane last month
blah but just divert yeah
solving problems we don't have yet right
but like when I can't keep people
straight and it's already gonna be there
for 20 people in there so having a
spreadsheet having something that is
here's the people here's their project
here's the people here's our project
here's an explainer video right and just
that simple then possibly once we have
more where I'm I'm giving you the
explainer video and my first where I'm
out of my project and then every monthly
one after that you can get spreadsheet
right on one column and it's like binge
watch me awesome like yeah as you said
it's still like solving problems before
we get there the first three videos or
five videos let's just have our go-to
pitch and all of them and then when it
gets annoying and when we're like
alright this is too much then we can say
great hopefully then we also have ten
other projects and we can start to build
that spreadsheet of here's each project
here's the don't adjust their elevator
pitch here's you know just a quick text
intro of what it is if you don't feel
like watching a video and then here's
the actual you know their their
playlists or their channel on their
YouTube channel showing all these videos
yep I really like solving problems we
don't have yet it's my favorite it's the
fun part solve all the problems they
don't have yet once I solved the problem
we have right now that's so hard it's
not that's kind of a brother
oh the next step the adjacent possible
life is like too easy I wanted to be
more difficult it didn't say that
oh don't do that there's the Court of
the day say that all right we are at the
hour so let's so one of us who wants to
take on posting it kind of in the basic
instructions in the projects Facebook
group and then the rest of us are gonna
put our videos under it so that people
can see this is what it looks like and
for participating and it helps the
algorithm and hopefully other people
participate as well but if they don't
great it's three of us and I'm fine
we're posting it I can be I'll post it
tonight and then I won't actually push
them up and let them love my my video
until probably the weekend but that way
we all kind of have some time to have
the instructions talk about the
instructions if I missed something
and then hopefully over time we'll stick
to see some videos trickle in well yeah
so so it's just a call-out for the video
less than five minutes explainer and
where you're at and your project right
and then we'll be looking to do these
monthly update you're pretty good or
yeah is monthly good or do we want to
start weekly is two one have more
content and then if they get to be too
much because you don't you think monthly
is good because my end goal is to have a
library of these things where like I'm
doing monthly when I'm also doing my
bi-weekly livestream I'm also gonna be
doing something else and something else
and I want to sort of have like a
collection of these things I'm trying
and then over time we you know if we
find that part of the feedback is you
know what that's so quick and it seems
useful it might end up being a weekly
thing
okay so monthly we might go to weekly
instead a weekly do I go to monthly
right I'm better with that I got a lot
going on it'll make a bit soon a video
every week a lot of other things
Center video awesome I'm going to post
the quiz up in Facebook right in the
game b14 Duck quiz Wow pull for what was
it for for our next project
solution raising which I want to be on
healthcare but I'll let I'll let the
people decide I'll talk on any of them
and and do we want that one that project
raising to be at 2 p.m. or 9:00 a.m. so
that's not tomorrow it's a week from
tomorrow
do you want to tragic yeah or at the
project raising I'm fine with you this
oh you Bentley so that would be the week
the Saturday after the Saturday yeah so
like the sixth or seventh so I think
seventh floor is the 29 yeah yeah that
should be fine I guess we can play in
this broadcast yeah all right bye
YouTube and Facebook
good bye both of you for the first time